士兵最强大的武器就是勇气
困境！
Stranded!
在共和国的一个秘密任务中
On a secret mission for the Republic,
Gascon上校带领他的铁皮人队伍
and his intrepid droid squad
成功从分离势力的船上偷到一个加密模块
successfully steal an encryption module
在逃跑的时候，我们英雄的飞船坠毁
During their escape, our heroes crash
在ABAFAR星系的外环附近
on the Outer Rim planet of Abafar
他们发现自己被困在一个奇怪的荒地中
and find themselves stranded
in the strange wasteland
维德在召唤
called The Void.
尽管困难重重，
Now, after surviving against all odds,
我们的英雄必须找到一条回家的路
our heroes must find a way home
把加密模块带回家
and deliver the encryption module
破解分离势力的密码，阻挡敌人的进攻
to crack the Separatist code
and stop an enemy attack.
我从没到过塔图恩星球（天行者的故乡）
I have never been to Tatooine,
R2,但如果这个地方让你想起那儿
but if this place
reminds you of it, Artoo,
记得提醒我不要去那里
remind me never to go there.
有礼貌些，呆头
Don't be absurd, Qutee.
这些人是无害的
These people aren't dangerous.
大部分人可能都藏起来了
Most of these people are probably hiding
为了躲避某个东西
from someone or something.
在外环的角落里有一条路
That's the way it is
on these Outer Rim armpits.
没人经过这里
Nobody's here by choice,
我也是第一次走
which goes double for me.
我希望你有一个计划
I hope you have a plan
带领我们走出这个困境，上校
to get us off this armpit, Colonel.
我当然会的，下士
Of course I do, Corporal.
我们必须找到一个通讯设备
All we need is a communications uplink
和一些燃料
and some fuel.
感谢你的提醒，C4
Thank you for the reminder, Ceefor,
但我很清楚飞船在维德受到的损害
but I'm well aware our shuttle's
lost in The Void.
我说的是我所需的燃料
I'm talking about fuel for me.
你们铁皮人可以互相分享电池能源
You droids can putter along
on battery power
但我需要食物充饥
but I need food to survive.
我的能量也正在耗尽
My power cells are running low too,
如果有换机油服务也挺好
and an oil bath would be nice.
这里的尘埃让我的关节磨损严重
All this dust is wreaking havoc
on my joints.
别期望了，电子人
Forget it, Beezee.
我们来这不是度假
We're not on vacation here.
R2,加密模块安全吗？
Artoo, is the encryption module safe?
肢解或死亡都不会
Nothing short of death or dismemberment
阻止GASON上校
will stop Colonel Meebur Gascon
把加密模块送到Coruscant
from delivering
that module to Coruscant.
嗯，我想也是
Well, I'll be.
一次晚餐，一个吃东西的地方
A diner.
A place of eating.
我获救了
[chuckles] I'm saved.
R2,你和其他铁皮人去周围戒备
Artoo, you and the other 'mechs
scout the perimeter.
看看附近是否有什么威胁
Find out if there
are any unfriendlies around.
下士，我和你都需要在这个地方补充燃料
Corporal, you and I will refuel
in this fine establishment.
真是好日子
Good day.
我是大共和帝国军队的GASON上校
I am Colonel Gascon of
the Grand Army of the Republic.
我来这里执行一个非常重要的任务
And I am here
on very important business.
我时间很紧，你是否能提供一份快餐给我
I don't have much time,
so if you'll be so kind
再帮我的铁皮人充一下电？
as to fix me your daily special
and let my droid recharge.
铁皮人没办法
No droids.
好的
Fine.
在外面等我，下士
Wait for me outside, Corporal.
对你们这种类型，我们也不提供服务
We don't serve your type either.
你适用于哪种类型？
What type are you referring to?
管道蠕虫
Conduit worms.
你说什么？ 我是一个ZIKAN
I beg your pardon.
I am a Zilkan.
你正在争取自己的生存
You'll be begging for your life
如果你不打它
if you don't beat it.
揍它
Beat it.
Uh-oh.
Ah!
Oh, ah!
很黄很暴力
This is an outrage.
那个怪物会为今天而感到后悔的
That monstrosity will rue the day
他拒绝为我提供食物
he denied me a meal.
我不想给它压力，上校
I would not push it, Colonel.
那个怪物可能会为你准备食物的
That monstrosity
might make a meal out of you.
我不在乎
[sighs] I don't care.
我感到饥饿
I'm famished.
我想我能提供帮助
I think I can help.
你的快餐准备好了，先生
Your meal awaits you, sir.
你的短接板
You short-circuiting
hydrospanner,
那不是食物
that's no meal.
那是垃圾
That is garbage.
有什么不同吗？
What is the difference?
它可以吃，不是吗？
It is edible, is it not?
Agh!
哦，对不起
Oh, uh, I'm sorry.
我没注意你在那里
I didn't see you there.
听着，我可以给你一些食物
Look, I could get you some food,
正常的人会从前门进来
but normally people
come in the front door.
但没问题
But there's no problem.
你知道你正在吃垃圾，对吧？
You do know that
you're eating garbage, right?
你是一个克隆人
You're a clone.
你说什么？
Excuse me?
嗯, 我--
我对此一无所知
I wouldn't know about that.
我的..我的名字是GREGOR
My--my name's Gregor.
嗯，等一下，克隆人是什么？
Uh, wait, what's a clone?
你就是一个克隆人
You are a clone.
你在进行间谍活动吗？
[laughs] Are you working undercover?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
听着，士兵，不管你的任务是什么
Listen to me, soldier,
whatever your assignment is,
也不可能比我的任务重要
it can't be more important than mine.
这是他第一次真正的任务
It is his first real mission.
他只是一个读图员
He is just a map reader.
别听那个笨蛋的话
Don't listen to that ignoramus.
你是一个克隆人，也是一个共和国军队里面的士兵
You are a clone and a soldier
in the Republic Army,
我命令你带我上你的飞船
and I order you to take me to your ship.
我们需要尽快回到Coruscant
We need to get back to Coruscant
immediately.
嗯，朋友，我只是想提供帮助而已
Uh, look, friend,
I was just trying to help.
如果你不误人子弟就好了
I'm sorry if you took it the wrong way.
我想那个士兵
I do not think that soldier
不相信你也是一个克隆，嗯，上校
believes you are a colonel, uh, Colonel.
Gregor!
干活去吧
Get back to work.
嗯，对不起，我必须走了
Uh, excuse me.
I got to go.
我不想失去我的工作
I don't want to lose my job.
但我还是很饿
But I'm still hungry.
嗯，有什么侦查报告吗？
Well, what's the scouting report?
分离势力的铁皮人？
Separatist droids?
嗯，那会让事情复杂化
Hmm, well, that complicates matters.
这样，嗯，老板
So, uh, boss,
你知道，我有个疑问...
you know, I was just wondering...
不，你得不到升职,Gregor
No, you can't have a raise, Gregor.
哦，不 不 不 不
Oh, no, no, no, no.
我不是想升职，先生
I don't want a raise, sir.
我-我只是想，克隆人是什么？
I-I just wanted to know,
what's a clone?
有人告诉我，我是一个克隆人
Someone told me I was a clone today.
他们很确信这点
They insisted.
嗯，一个克隆人？
Heh.
A clone?
克隆人在星系间战斗
Clones fight battles across the galaxy.
他们是勇敢的战士
They are brave soldiers.
你和他们有何相似之处？
Does that sound like you?
你是一个洗碗工，Gregor.
You're a dishwasher, Gregor.
忘了克隆人或相关事情
Forget about clones
or anything like that.
你在这有美好的生活
You have good life here,
一个简单的生活
a simple life.
在伯克斯发现你的时候就开始了
More than you had when Borkus found you.
我知道，先生
I know, sir.
我很欣赏你所做的每件事情
And I appreciate everything
that you've done.
相信我
Believe me.
但我想，也许你--
But I thought
maybe you could--
能不能告诉我，我是怎么到这儿的？
could you tell me, how did I get here?
你在哪里找到我的？
Where did you find me?
问题够多了
Enough questions.
回家去睡觉吧
Go home. Sleep.
明天再回来干活
Come back tomorrow.
Do your job.
而我不想再听到任何和“克隆人”有关的话语
And I don't ever want to hear
that word "clone" again,
明白了吗？
understand?
不得不说，我们经在
I cannot help noticing
执行我们的第三个计划了
that we are already on our third plan.
小型战斗需要灵活机动和及时应变的策略
Smart battle strategy requires
flexibility and improvisation,
这些都是铁皮人所缺乏的特质
something droids are not known for.
R2说的对
Artoo is right.
铁皮人缺少变通
Droids are not known for being flexible,
因为我们的程序早就已经固化了
because we are programmed
to be right the first time.
那么，下士，请回答这个问题
Well, answer me this, Corporal,
如果绝地委员会认为某个铁皮人
if the Jedi Council
thought one of you droids
更适合执行这次任务
were better prepared
to lead this mission,
那为什么他们又让我来指挥呢？
then why did they put me in charge?
因为只有你才能钻进铁罐里面
'Cause you were the only one
who could fit inside Beezee.
不，是因为我拥有推理能力
No, it is because my power
of deduction told me
比如说，在ABAFAR星球看见铁皮人
that if there
are Separatist droids on Abafar,
我就可以推断出附近肯定有一个着陆点，
then there must be a landing zone nearby
而那里绝对有一艘可以带我们回家的飞船
where there will be no doubt
a shuttle to take us home.
那才是我作为指挥官的原因，下士
That, Corporal, is why I am in charge.
现在，我们偷偷下到那儿，别被发现哦
Now, we are going
to waltz down there, undetected,
就像上次我们在战舰中所做的一样
just like we did on the dreadnought,
然后占领那艘飞船，我不希望发生意外
and commandeer that shuttle
without incident.
铁皮人有个想法，上校
The 'mechs have a point, Colonel.
自从我们上次战舰行动以后
After what we did on the dreadnought,
那些战斗机器人可能已经暴露身份
those battle droids probably
have our identities scanned.
这次我们不得不打开一条血路才能登舰了
We will have to fight our way
onto the shuttle this time.
嗯，你们铁皮人可能有自己的看法
Hmm, you droids may have a point.
但没有捷径可走
But there's no way in Malachor
我准备带领这支可怜的小分队
that I'm going to lead
this pitiful squad
对那个着陆点进行一次攻击
on an assault of that landing zone.
上校，你有什么计划？
What is the plan now, Colonel?
我要等到我们的克隆人下班
We're going to wait
until our clone gets off work,
才能取得他的帮助，不管他愿不愿意
then enlist his help,
whether he wants to or not.
REX上尉报到
Captain Rex reporting for duty.
啊！什么？
Agh! What?
我...
I...
我不明白
I don't understand.
那是我自己？
That's me?
不，那是REX上尉
No, that's Captain Rex.
他是共和国军队的克隆人士兵
He's a clone in the Republic Army,
就像你一样，Gregor.
just like you, Gregor.
真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
OK, 别急，放松
Okay, slow down.
Slow down.
你是说还有更多这样的克隆人？
So you're telling me that there
are more of these clones?
数以百万。整个军队都是
Millions.
A whole army's worth.
Uh-huh.
他们看起来和我一模一样？
And they all look exactly like me?
不，那些克隆人都是战士，
No, those clones are warriors,
由共和国创造的职业军人，
professional soldiers
created by the Republic,
训练有素，勇敢无畏
trained to fight, and die if necessary,
在我们对抗分离势力的战争中建功立业
in our war against the Separatists.
他们不是在害虫出没的洞穴中
They're not dishwashers
生活的洗碗工。
living in
some vermin-infested hovel.
听着，能在这里生活，我觉得很幸运
Look, I'm lucky to live in this place.
博克斯先生说我的薪水不包括房租
Mr. Borkus says my salary
doesn't even cover the rent,
他对我特殊优待
so he pays the difference for me.
难道你不明白，Gregor?
Don't you get it, Gregor?
你是他的奴隶
You're his slave.
我们需要找到你的归属
We need to figure out
who you really are,
你如何来到这里
how you got here.
你确定你不能记起任何事情？
Are you sure
you don't remember anything?
嗯，我记得我在一辆运输船上醒来
Well, all I remember is
waking up on a transport.
因为某种原因我们坠毁在ABAFAR星球
Somehow we crashed on Abafar.
还有，博克斯先生说我有健忘症
And, well, Mr. Borkus says
I have amnesia.
嗯
Hmm.
每个克隆人手腕上都有识别码
Every clone has an
identifying code on their wrist.
你在军队服役的记录都在数据库里面
Your military records
will be in the database.
扫描他，R2
Scan him, Artoo.
真令人吃惊，
Impressive.
Gregor, 你的型号是CC-5576-39.
your designation
is CC-5576-39.
你曾在一支精英小分队里服役，上尉军衔
You were a captain
and part of an elite squad.
一个克隆人指挥官
A clone commando.
你的资料显示
Your file says you were reported
你在一次战斗中失踪
missing in action during
萨里斯战役
the Battle of Sarrish.
萨里斯?
萨里斯.
等一下
萨里斯战役是什么？
What was the Battle of Sarrish?
它是共和国军队损失惨重的战役之一
It was one of the Republic's
most devastating losses.
萨里斯战役
是的
Yes.
是的，我记起来了
Yes, I remember now.
很多士兵死亡
So many soldiers were dying.
你记得你是如何逃离萨里斯战役的吗？
Dodo you remember
how you escaped Sarrish?
记不起了
No.
我只记得一眼望去全是尸体
I just remember seeing all those bodies.
漫山遍野的尸体
Bodies everywhere.
我只记得我必须寻求帮助
I knew I had to get help.
但记忆就在这里中断了
But that's where the memory stops.
好吧，士兵
Well, soldier,
现在你对那场战役也帮不上什么忙
there's nothing you can do
about that battle now,
但你能帮助我们
but you can help us.
我们的任务全靠它了
Our mission depends on it.
嗯，上校，Gregor刚才说给他5分钟考虑
Uh, Colonel, Gregor said
to give him five minutes,
但现在已经6分钟了
but it has been six.
如果他不愿意加入我们怎么办？
What if he does not accept
your offer to join us?
那么我会回到那儿
Then I'll go back in there
亲自灌输一些理念给他
and personally
knock some sense into him.
那没必要吧
That won't be necessary.
Whoa!
让我的外表看起来象一个士兵
I figured
at least looking like a soldier
也许能带回更多的记忆
might bring back some more memories,
不管怎样，首先要找回我的装备
until we recover my equipment anyway.
我听到你们这些家伙的谈话
I overheard you guys talking.
我想我知道我的武器在哪了
I think I know where my armor is.
让我们检查一下餐厅
Let's go check out the diner.
动起来，士兵们。这不是舞会
Step it up, soldiers.
This isn't a party.
我们没有整晚的时间
We do not have all night.
再找这个？
Looking for this?
我的制服  我的装备
My uniform.
My equipment.
一直以来你都知道我是谁，而不告诉我
All this time you knew who I was
and didn't tell me.
为什么？
Why?
我不在乎你是谁
I don't care who you were.
你现在就是洗碗工
You are dishwasher now.
而且是我把你从坠毁事故中救出来
And you owe me for saving you
from your crash.
你的命是我的，Gregor.
Your life is mine, Gregor.
你没有救我
You didn't save me.
你把我变成一个奴隶
You turned me into a slave.
我一直在这个垃圾场工作，听你发号施令
I've worked in this dump
taking orders from you
本来我应该为共和国而去战斗
when I could have been fighting
for the Republic.
我要恢复我自己的生活
I want my life back.
你想要你的自由，Gregor？
You want your freedom, Gregor?
从我这里拿起你的枪
Take your gun from me.
向我展示一下你是一个士兵
Show me you are a soldier.
明白了吗？
You see?
你不再是士兵
You are no soldier.
你是一个洗碗工
You are a dishwasher.
啊，你们这些破铜烂铁
Why, you no-good droids.
放开我
Let go of me.
Agh! Oh.
Agh!
拿上你的东西，Gregor.
Take your things, Gregor.
我们一起离开这里
We're getting out of here.
别走，Gregor.
Don't leave, Gregor.
外面是浩渺无限的星系
It's a big galaxy out there,
比你想象的还要大
bigger than you know.
留下来，你的生活很简单
Stay here, where your life is simple.
对这个克隆人来说
Simple isn't good enough anymore.
简单不再美好了
Not for this clone.
Ha!
你永远不能离开ABAFAR
You will never get off Abafar,
你和你的这些共和国朋友都如此
you and your little Republic friends,
你们的绝地巡逻舰爆炸之后就注定了
not after your Jedi cruiser blows up.
你究竟在讲什么？
What are you talking about?
你认为分离势力为什么来这里？
Why do you think the
Separatists bother coming here?
他们正在挖矿，名叫Rhydonium
They are mining our Rhydonium
把矿物装上自己的飞船，然后破坏你们的巡逻舰
to load on the shuttle
and destroy your ride home.
走着瞧
You will see.
你们全会困在这里
You will all be stuck here
乞求博克斯在他的餐厅留个工作岗位给自己
begging Borkus for a job in his diner.
OK,让我们瞧瞧我们面对的是什么
Okay, let's see what we're up against.
Gregor.
等一下，那儿
Wait.
There.
有一艘巡洋舰在那边
There's a cruiser up there.
我想，就是那艘飞船
And that shuttle, I think--
是的，它正在装运矿物Rhydonium
Yes, it's being loaded up
with Rhydonium canisters.
Huh.
我想博克斯先生
I guess Mr. Borkus
实际上没有说谎，至少这次如此
was actually telling
the truth...for once.
Rhydonium是什么矿物？
What exactly is Rhydonium?
它是一种能源矿
It's a fuel.
大部分产自ABAFAR这里
Mostly been mined out on Abafar.
极不稳定，而且危险
It's volatile and dangerous.
是的，现在我们有一个新任务：
Yes, we do have a new mission:
阻止分离势力炸毁那艘巡逻舰
Stop the Separatists
from blowing up that cruiser.
上校，我会掩护你，清理出一条道路
I'll cover you
and clear the way, Colonel.
你们所有人直接冲上飞船
You all head straight to the shuttle.
我来对付那些铁皮人
I'll take care of those clankers.
嗯，听起来像个好计划
Hmm, sounds like a good plan.
你的士兵准备浴血奋战了吗？
You soldiers ready to get dangerous?
我会在飞船上和你碰头，先生
I'll meet you at the shuttle, sir.
我们出发
Let's roll.
Hey!
你需要授权进入这个区域
You need authorization
to enter this area.
Agh!
消灭他们！
Get them!
Agh!
干得好，Gregor.
Good job, Gregor.
看，他在那里！
Look, he's up there!
继续前进
Just keep moving.
一切尽在控制中
It is all under control.
我开始记得我有多么憎恨这些家伙
I'm beginning to remember
how much I hate these guys.
嘿，我不能识别那些太空人
Hey, I don't recognize those astromechs.
干掉他们！
Blast them!
他们在冲向我们
They are on to us.
上校，你能听见我说话吗？
Colonel, can you hear me?
自求多福！
Save yourselves!
Okay.
Whoa!
Agh!
Whoa-oh-oh.
[blasters firing]
每个人都到这了吗？
Did everybody make it?
不，铁皮人和上校还在外面
No, Beezee and the colonel
are still out there.
发动飞船引擎
Get the shuttle ready to roll.
Agh!
上校，你没事吧？
Colonel, you all right?
我也许不能活着回去了
I'll never make it back alive.
不，你可以的，先生
Yes, you will, sir.
我天生就注定要这样
This is what I was born to do.
快,趁现在还不晚
Now, go before it's too late.
我很高兴能和你一起战斗，上校
It's been an honor
serving with you, Colonel.
R2说得对
Artoo's right.
我们可以打个回马枪，再把你接回去
We can swing back around
and pick you up.
别担心我
Don't worry about me.
你让我记得我是谁
You made me remember who I am.
我发誓，我会回家的
I'll make my way home.
I promise.
现在，出发！
Now go!
Gregor在哪？
Where is Gregor?
他在履行一个士兵的义务
He's doing what a soldier does:
牺牲他自己，换取其他战友的生命
sacrificing himself
for the lives of others.
你将会被铭记在心。Gregor上尉
You will be remembered, Captain Gregor.
我们会把你的英雄事迹在共和国内传播
We will take your heroic story
back to the Republic,
我们会等待你的回归
and we will watch for your return.
翻译：hdtvguy
欢迎传播！违者不究！